刚那是非常短的一杆推杆
It was a very short putt.
鉴于之前一洞已多于标准杆一杆
It would seem routine had
这一杆反而显得有些剑走偏锋
he not just come off a bogey the hole before.
失误在先显然令他有些沮丧
Mm-hmm, obviously smarting from that.
不过我们来看看这一杆他怎么处理
But let's see what he does here.
教科书般完美无缺  完美无缺
Oh perfect. Textbook, textbook.
现在去看看第七球道上李・特拉维诺的情况
We move ahead now to Lee Trevino on the fairway at the seventh.
从他的杆底角看  似乎下方草皮有断片
His lie looks as though he may be in a little divot.
显然如此  巡回赛官员正在严加斥责
Absolutely. Tournament officials have been cracking down
负责填补的球童
on caddies filling in the divots.
在这样高水平的比赛中
At this level of the game,
高尔夫的规范制度也愈加彰显
some of us gotta watch the etiquette of golf.
睡吧
Just go to sleep.
漂亮的近距切球
A lovely approach.
他在斟酌  我想这般优秀...
He's considering it now. I presume that a player like...
沙杆还是中号劈起杆
Sand wedge or intermediate pitching wedge.
真让人激动  他正在瞄准
Oh, very exciting. He's lining up the shot.
看着我
Look at me.
什么
Hmm?
我受不了了
I'm not standing for this.
什么
Sorry?
你禁锢了我的灵魂
You keep my soul in a dungeon.
我要离开你
I'm leaving.
杰克
Jack?
-杰克  -你走我就把她扔下去
- Jack. - If you leave me, I'll throw her.
你觉得我不敢是吗
You think that I won't, hmm?
-求你了  -你觉得我不敢是吗
- Please. - Do you think I won't?!
我不走  不离开你
I won't leave. I won't leave you.
对不起  别再那样做
I'm sorry. Don't ever do that again.
别离开我  别再那样做
Don't ever leave me. Don't ever do that again.
光明美丽遍大地
All things bright and beautiful.
浩瀚渺小皆苍生
All creatures great and small.
聪慧美好满人间
All things wise and wonderful.
上主慈悲万物生
The Lord God made them all.
请各位就座
I invite you to be seated at this time.
非常漂亮的补杆
Oh, that's a very nice touch.
那或许他可以保住标准杆
So maybe he can make a par. And at worse from there
之后再糟糕应该也能保住总杆数标准杆
you'd think he could stay his point total.
他现在却在这个标准三杆的洞使用七号铁杆
Now here we find him with a 7-iron at this par-3 hole.
铁杆：用金属做的杆，用作中距离的击球
杆号越小，球击得越远
我不知道是不是他右脚打滑的原因
I don't know if there was a problem with him slippin' with
但那绝对应该是个左旋球
his right foot there, but definitely a pull.
显然他心中早有打算
He obviously had the thought in his head
想要出其不意
that he needed to give it a little bit extra,
如今却陷入困境
and he's found himself in a difficult spot.
他对这场比赛的全部期望...
All the expectations he had coming into this,
-喂  -杰克
- Hello? - Jack.
贝西
Betsy.
你哥哥去世了
Your brother slipped away.
终于脱离苦海了
Finally out of his misery.
-是的  -我懂  我懂
- Yes, he is. - Oh, I know, I know.
我一次次听到这样的话语
And how many times did I hear,
"你为什么不能像你哥哥鲍比那样"
"Why can't you be like your brother Bobby"?
要是每听一次这句话我就有一毛钱进帐
If I had a nickel for every time that was said to me...
想必我也发达了
I'd be a rich man today.
对于他前额上的那一块伤疤
That scar on his forehead that he had,
他总能讲出一个渊源
he always had a story for it,
但其实罪魁祸首是我
but it was me.
我八岁时砸了这位完美先生一锤头
I threw a hammer at Mr. Perfect when I was eight.
但为了庇护他爱的人  他绝口不提
He never told though. He covered for the people he loved.
我爱着这样的他  他就是这样一个人
That's how he was and I loved him for that.
我希望能像他一样
And I wanted to be like him.
方方面面
Everything-
我只想说...
I just want to say that...
若不是鲍比  我...
If it wasn't for Bobby, I'd...
我不知道...
I- I don't know...
自己会是何种境地
Where I would've wound up.
他教会我生活  明辨是非
He taught me how to live, what was right.
我会怀念他
I'm gonna miss him.
他一生无憾  一生无憾  他...
He lived right. He lived right. He was...
人生至此  夫复何求
What more could you s- want people to say about you?
圣经通篇描述上帝如何公正
All throughout Scripture it talks about God being a just God.
可我刚读了一个寓言
I mean, I just read the parable
讲述了一个女人不停地前来诉说
about the unjust judge,
其中的决断就有失公允
where the woman kept coming and coming and saying...
关怀  爱意  宽容
Caring, loving, forgiving...
我怀疑你是否真心赞同那些言论
I'm wondering if you concur with what you've heard so far?
我认为关于选择  关于自由意志...
I think that the choices, the idea of free will,
以及我们有选择的自由...
and the fact that we have freedom of choice...
如今我们生活的时代
The reality of the times we live in,
充斥着焦躁和不安
this notion that- this angst
片名:  《色狱心机》
举国上下多少人内心波澜起伏
that a lot of people are feeling in this country,
忧心于我们经历了某种根本性转变
that we've gone through some sort of fundamental transformation...
今日早些时候
"Barack Obama earlier today,
巴拉克・奥巴马将其五个月前
crediting his so-called stimulus package
签署的所谓刺激计划标榜为
that he signed four or five months ago,
"把现金送进纳税人的口袋"
as "Putting cash into the pockets of taxpayers. "
如果作为底特律地区的纳税人的您
If you're a taxpayer in the Detroit area
拿到了刺激计划送来的现金
who got cash in your pocket from the stimulus plan,
请打电话给我
I'd love to hear from ya,
当然您也可以通过网络联系我们
and you can also check in via the internet,
但我们期待听到您的亲口描述
but we would love to hear from you personally.
沃伦市的凯文  接通凯文
Kevin in Warren. We go to Kevin.
凯文  感谢来电
Kevin thanks so much for calling.
非常荣幸
Welcome.
你好  帕姆
Hi, Pam.
谢谢
Thanks.
不  是真的
No, it's true.
上帝作证  我改过自新了
With God is my witness, I've changed.
以耶稣和家人的名义...
With Jesus and my family...
主啊  以前的事我很后悔
Oh my God, I'm sorry for what I've done.
搞了把玩具枪把酒品店给抢了
I mean, I robbed a goddamn liquor store with a toy gun.
哪个傻帽干这种蠢事啊
What kinda- what kinda idiot does that?
监狱长找你
Warden wants to see you.
你好  艾利
Hi, Allie.
-你好  米曲  杰尼斯  -杰克
- Hi, Mitch. Janice. - Jack.
-什么事  -关门  杰克
- What's up? - Shut the door, Jack.
这个叫迪肖恩・麦克尼的
This Deshawn Mackey guy.
由你负责  这是你的报告  对吧
This is yours? Your report, right?
对  怎么了
Yeah. Yeah. Why?
简直一团糟  杰克
It's an incompetent mess, Jack.
我知道你的心早就飞到高尔夫球场上了
I mean, look, I know your head's already out on the golf course,
但这份报告简直是有辱斯文
but this is a travesty of proper casework here.
-骗到你了  -确实
- I got ya. - You got me.
给  跟言简意赅的大师学学
Here. Learn from the master of understatement.
-一定  -要简洁
- Absolutely. - Keep 'em brief.
得趁你走人之前
Now I need to get Janice
让杰尼斯熟悉起来
up to speed before you're out the back door,
所以就把你手上未定的审核都交给她吧
so let's pass all your indeterminates eligible off to her.
好的  当然  但我手头已经审核的案子
Yeah yeah, of course, but I'd like to stay on my currents,
我想坚持做完他们的复查阶段  可以吗
if I can see them through to review- is that okay?
当然  只要你愿意
Yeah, if you're willing.
-我很愿意  谢谢  -好的
- I would like to. Thank you. - Yeah.
-没事了  -好
- We're good. - Okay.
节哀顺变
Oh, hey, I'm sorry.
什么
Excuse me?
你哥哥  我才听说  请节哀顺变
Your brother- I just recently heard, I'm sorry.
多谢关心
Thank you.
-好的  -好
- Okay. - Yeah.
石头
S- Stone.
什么
Hmm?
不是  我叫石头
No, I-I'm Stone.
我知道文件里写的"杰拉德"
I mean, I know it say "Gerald" In the file,
但我更喜欢石头这个名号
but I'm just saying I prefer Stone.
杰拉德・科里森
Gerald Creeson.
石头算怎么回事  外号吗
So what's Stone, like a nickname?
是监狱里的外号吗
That's something from here?
不  不是  老兄  让那帮湃巳ニ
No. Oh no, man. Fuck ail these assholes.
那些认得我的人才这么叫我
Yo, that's what my people call me. You know, people who know me.
我们不会就这样
Look, are we just gonna,
拿张表勾勾叉叉吧?
like- are you just gonna tick the boxes and shit?
就不能有话直说吗
I mean, can we- can we talk straight?
你到底帮不帮我出去
I mean, you gonna help me out or what?
你懂不懂  我觉得
'Cause I, you know, I don't think
这破牢我已经蹲够本儿了
I deserve to be up in here no more.
说慢点  慢点  慢点
Let's just slow down. Slow slow down.
我磨了够久了  再来三年也不能...
I've done a long bid, man. Three more years ain't gonna-
说慢点  来谈谈你为什么来蹲牢吧
Slow down. Let's - let's talk about what got you here.
来讲讲吧
You want to tell me about that?
不就在你面前吗
It's right there in front of you.
干嘛还要说一遍
Why you want to talk about that again?
因为现在你攥在我手里
'Cause now you're mine.
你进入下一级审核了
You moved up.
还有  我就是喜欢聊天
And just 'cause I like to chat.
里面那帮二逼
All these scrubs in here,
那帮短刑期的  还有那些软柿子
you know, these short-timers and meatballs,
都装出一副被冤枉的样子  对不对
they're like, they're all innocent, right?
至少我承认了
Yeah. But at least I admit it.
我当时就承认了自己的罪过
You know, I copped to what I did right away,
现在该往前看了  老兄
and-and now I'm lookin' forward, man.
我外面有工作等着  我就不明白了
I got a job lined up and I'm sayin',
这种屁话要说多少遍才算个头
why I got to talk about that shit every fuckin' time?
因为我想听你自己说出来  没其他原因
'Cause I want to hear your side of it, that's why.
猜怎么着  操他妈的狗屁事  操你妈
You know what? Just fuck this shit. Fuck you too.
-我他妈没空陪你玩  -小子
- I ain't got time for this bullshit. - Hey, son-
你丫压根就没想让我通过
No, you're just settin' them up so they can flop me, man.
你爱写什么随便写  不同意就不同意吧
So you write what you're gonna write and let's just get on with it, man.
-哥无所谓  -小子  石头
- 'Cause I'll take the flop. - Hey, son. Stone.
-你写啊  写不同意啊  写啊  -小子  别激动
- Go ahead, max me, max me. - Son, calm down.
你以为我怕你啊  随你他妈怎么写
You don't think I'll do it, I'll see that max standing
-哥才不怕你  -石头
- on my fucking head, man. - Stone!
出去以后有你好看  贱人
I'll see you outside before you see me, bitch.
石头  两秒以后
Stone!
你他妈就会回牢里蹲着
In about two fucking seconds you're gonna go in the hole,
而你的档案也会被压在最底下
and your file is gonna go to the bottom of my pile.
明白吗  看见面前那扇门没
You understand? You see that door in front of you?
你知道出门意味着什么  回监狱
You know where it goes- back.
你想重回监狱  随便你
You want to go back? Be my guest.
想开始新生活  想出去看新世界
You want to go forward, you want to walk out of here,
想找到那扇门吗  我  我就是那扇门
you want to find that door? Me, I'm that door.
你得通过我
And you will go through me.
哪怕我问起天气
If I ask you a question about the weather,
你他妈也得乖乖回答
you better fucking answer it
否则咱们三年后再见
or go back and I'll see you in three years.
-明白没  -明白
- You got it? - Yeah.
-那你他妈就坐下  -好
- Then sit the fuck down. - All right.
都没事了
Well, we just shootin' the shit.
我喜欢她  够劲儿
I like her, man. She's hard.
好  行了  听我说
Okay. All right, look,
程序就是这样
look, this is a process.
我们聊聊
We talk.
我们不是朋友  那就装成朋友  好吗
We're not friends, but just pretend we're friends, okay?
放松  随便聊聊  就这样
Relax, just-just talk, that's all,
说不定咱们就能各得其所  好吗
and then maybe we both get what we want, okay?
-行  那就装吧  -好
- Okay, let's pretend. - Okay.
你结婚了
You're married.
对
Yeah.
那很好
Okay, that's good.
你结婚多久了
How long are you married?
九年了  八年就在这儿耗了
Nine years, man- eight of it up in this shit.
材料里写过了  老兄  我不想...
It's right in the file, man. I don't want-
说说你的妻子
Let's talk about your wife.
-露西塔  -对
- Lucetta? - Mm-hmm, yeah.
-她来过这里没  你见过她没  -没有
- Has she come up here? You seen her? - No.
-她正点到爆  兄弟  -什么意思
- She's a dime, dawg. - What's a dime?
完美情人  她很好
Perfect 10, man. She's fine.
我偷偷跟你说
I'll tell you, between you and me,
她很不同一般
she's-she's a alien.
不同一般  她是外国来的非法移民吗
Alien? What do you mean, like an illegal?
不  不是非法移民  她比你还白呢
No, she ain't illegal, man. She's whiter than you.
她就像是  就像是
No, she's like- she's like a-
从另一个世界来的
she's an alien from another world, man.
她常来看你吗  周六给你带便当吗
She visit you much? Picnics most Saturdays?
我讨厌便当  我喜欢干她
I don't want no picnic, man. I miss my dick in her fuckin' ass.
我无比怀念口交时那种欲仙欲死的感觉
You know, I miss her suckin' me till I can't take no more.
她疯的很  什么都肯做
I mean, she's crazy. She'll do anything.
乳交  颜射都无所谓
Fuck her tits, come in her face,
她也就眨眨眼  笑个不停
she'll just blink and keep on laughing, man.
她就是...
It's- she-
你要真想聊露西塔
look, if we gonna talk about Lucetta,
可得做好心理准备
you better watch out,
接下来给你描述的事儿
'cause I'm gonna give you some pictures in your head
估计要让你性奋得好几夜睡不着了
gonna keep you up nights, man.
不会吧
Oh man.
对不起  对不起  我说话漏风  我知道
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I- I got a mouth, I know.
我的错  老兄  你现在看我那眼神
I apologize, man. You're givin' me that look,
感觉就像是审核到此为止了
and I feel like you go down here and that's the end of this shit.
这样  我可不想惹你
Look, I don't want no beef with you.
我好好待着
I just want to be vegetarian.
那是你老婆吗
Is that your wife? You're married?
对
Yeah.
-很久了吗  -四十三年了
- A long time? - 43 years.
不会吧
Get the fuck out.
看来是真爱了
Man, that's true love, huh?
真好  四十三年了
That's great, and after 43 years
还有激情干柴烈火什么的
and you still get it on and everything?
-你说什么  -不是  我是真好奇
- Excuse me? - No, I'm really curious about this.
是这样  我爱我的马子
It's like, say, I love my lady, right,
但有时候想想
but, you know, I wonder sometimes,
要是她以后满身满脸的褶子可怎么办
like how you gonna do when the skin starts to go to the crepe,
你明白我意思吗
you know what I'm sayin'? I mean,
你一般怎么搞
what do- how does that work for you?
要吃点伟哥硬起来还是怎样
Like you get hip to Viagra, so you can like hammer nails with it?
等等  你听好
Listen listen, look, I don't
我不跟人这样讨论我老婆
talk with anybody about my wife like that.
我没说你老婆  我在说我自己
I ain't talkin' about your wife. I'm sayin', for me,
我关在这里很多年了
you know, I've been locked up a long time.
现在让我去干
You don't need much more
估计没两下就不行了
than two pumps and a swirl to get it done.
嘴巴干净点
I don't consider this polite conversation.
我没想显粗鲁  我只想知道
I ain't tryin' to be rude, okay? I really want to know
你能量释放到哪里
where does that go?
或者说发泄到哪里
Or where do you put it, if you-
你懂我的意思不
you get what I'm sayin'?
我想知道你怎么处理这事
I want to know how it works for you,
怎么把那把火压住
how you keep a lid on that.
现在不是谈我的时候
We're not- we're not talking about me.
不谈我  懂不懂
We're not talking about me, okay?
人类看表象
Man looks on the outward appearance.
上帝看心灵
God looks on the heart.
当然人的心灵确实很重要
And certainly the heart of a man does matter,
因为口中所言皆由心生
because out of the abundance of the heart the mouth speaks...
选择是上帝决意呈现给我们的
Only in the choices that God decides to present to us.
不对  我不是那意思
Well, no, I'm not saying that.
我是说我相信人是有主观能动性的
I'm saying that I just believe that we're automatons...
事情就是这样
...and here's the deal:
-我没有选择出生  -很严肃的
- I did not choose to be born... - This is very very serious.
我也无法选择再出生一次
...and I cannot choose to be born again.
她都四岁了  你相信吗
She's four- can you believe it?
诸如此类的事情上我没有选择权
I had no choice in that matter whatsoever, and yet
-却有很多人...  -你去哪儿了
- there are so many people that... - Where have you gone?
认为他们在灵魂再生
...think they have a choice in the matter
和灵魂形成上可以选择
of their spiritual rebirth and their spiritual formation.
事实上
The fact of the matter is,
生命种子埋下  受孕完成
a seed is planted and conception takes place,
-而你只能顺应天命  -阿门
- which you had nothing to do with. - Amen.
上帝之声  WDDL广播电台
All Voices Under God, WDDL,
几条重要消息后再回来
will continue here right after these very important messages.
当时我们嗑嗨了  想找钱
Look, we was high as shit and we were lookin' for money.
爷爷听到我们的声音
You know? My poppy hears us.
他和迪奇说了几句
Him and Teach have words.
爷爷去别处拿了枪
Poppy goes and gets his gun.
我就想"搞毛  我可不想搀和进来"
And I was like, "Fuck this. I don't want no part of this,"
于是我就出去了
and I went outside.
然后迪奇把事情处理了  房子也烧了
So then, Teach done what he done and then the house got burnt.
实在是...糟透了
It was- you know, it was terrible.
我当时就知道自己犯了大错
I was like a terrible mistake that I made.
悲惨极了但也已经过去很久了
I was tragic and it was a long time ago
我为此付出了...
and I've paid- I've paid...
太长时间的煎熬
With a lot of hard time.
我想现在我准备好出去了
And I just think, you know, I'm so ready to be out
开始新生活
and start my life again,
所以...
and well, so what-
我们要怎怎怎么做才能实现
you know, what-what-what can we do to make that happen?
怎样你才会帮我实现
How can you help me make that happen?
看情况吧
Well, we'll see.
这才刚开始  所以
We were just getting started, so-
我来这里变好了不少  你知道吗
A lot of good things have happened for me in here, you know.
我考了GED[相当于高中水平]
I did my GED like that, man.
我在纺织工厂里改造
I held down this job- Textiles Unit,
过去的两年一直是第一名
number one position the last two years.
我要回家找我的妻子
I'm goin' home to my wife.
她都给我找好工作了
She's got a spot for me, you know,
在埃勒特山的克莱斯勒汽车厂
Mount Elliot Chrysler,
工作都准备好了
job lined up.
我想去  你知道吗
I'm-I'm going, you know.
是的  这是谁的主意
Yeah, whose idea was it?
露西塔  她认识
Lucetta- she knows
埃勒特山分店的经理
the branch manager at Mount Elliot.
不  不是你的工作
No no, not your job.
要去你祖父母家是谁的主意
Whose idea was it to go to your grandparent's?
-什么  -是谁的主意
- What? - Whose idea was it?
我告诉过你  我告诉过你  是迪奇
I told you- I told you it was Teach.
迪奇  你知道
Teach, you know.
就像我说的  我甚至没有...
Like I said, I wasn't even...
我一直就在屋子外面
I was...I went outside the house.
是的  但是你没有阻止他们  对吧
Yeah, but you didn't stop them, did you?
-阻止他们什么  -杀害你的祖父母
- Stop 'em what? - From killing your grandparents.
你根本不想让我通过是吧  哥们
You-you-you ain't gonna do it, man.
你不会...
You're not gonna-
你知道个屁啊  见鬼
You don't give a fuck, man. Shit.
我当时在外面
I was outside,
迪奇出来了
Teach...Teach come out,
直到他告诉我  我才知道他做了什么
and I didn't even know what he'd done until he told me.
迪奇都已经作证了  哥们
Teach testified to that, man.
这就是为什么我没有被判谋杀罪
He- that's why I didn't even catch the rap for...for manslaughter.
而只是帮凶和纵火罪
I got accessory and arson.
我已经蹲了八年了
I've done eight out of 10-15.
你们到底想让我怎么样
I mean, what...what more do you want from me?
好吧  这样
Okay, so,
我们要让今天
let's make today
成为又一个异常特殊的日子
an extra special day.
让我们为某人做一件好事
Let's do one nice thing for someone else,
但是不告诉任何人我们做过  好吗
but not tell anyone else that we did it, okay?
好的
Okay.
要是拿7-2牌的人赢了  每人给十块钱
Win with the seven-deuce, it's 10 bucks for everybody.
7-2  Poker里面最不可能赢的组合
所以必须有特殊规则来保护
否则拿到这种牌的人会直接放弃  也就是fold
分高低彩池都赢的话
Win both ways with the seven-deuce,
-每人二十块  -杰克狂野吗
- 20 bucks a head. - Jack's wild?
他当然不狂野
Jack's definitely not wild.
玛莎  跟进吗
Marsha, stay in?
你好
Hello?
请问这是杰克・玛布里的家吗
Hi, is this Jack Mabry's place?
什么
Excuse me?
我叫露西塔・科里森
Oh, my name is Lucetta Creeson.
我的丈夫...
My husband's...
对不起  我没听明白
Excuse me, I couldn't understand what-
我想找杰克・玛布里
Can I speak to Jack Mabry?
我是玛布里夫人
Well, this is Mrs. Mabry.
好的  我能跟杰克对话吗
Okay, can I speak to Jack?
你要找我丈夫的话  我可以给他带个话
You need my husband. I can give him a mess-
-你找到他了吗  -跟他太太说了几句
- Hey, you get ahold of him? - She was a little short.
我也不知道
You know? Like, I don't know.
她好像不想跟我说什么
Like she didn't want to talk or something.
你为什么和她说话呢
Why-why-why you talkin' to her?
嘿  汤米  我们不能咬
Hey, Tommy, Tommy, we don't bite.
不能咬  好吗
Huh-uh, no biting, okay?
你明白我在说什么吗
Do you understand what I'm sayin'?
我现在需要你帮我
I need you to do this for me right now.
就现在  别让机会溜走
Right now. Don't let it slide.
好的  我会的
Okay, I will.
好吗  今晚给他打电话
Okay? Call him tonight.
明天还给他打  明天晚上还给他打
Call him tomorrow. Call him tomorrow night.
后天还给他打  后天晚上还打
Call him the day after. Call him the day after tomorrow night.
我想知道
That's what I'm getting
你承认你之前做错了吗
at is do you believe what you did was wrong?
你在想什么  就因为我在西部长大
What-what d'you think, because I grew up westside
我就是不能分辨是非的
that like I'm one of these socio-delinquent types,
社会问题青年
don't know the difference between right and wrong?
你想知道我的悲惨童年和狗屎命运吗
You want me to tell you about my bad childhood and shit?
我不知道  你曾经有吗
I don't know. Did you have one?
你知道  在那时
Well, you know, at the time,
我认为干坏事都是正常的
I thought a lot of shit was normal.
这当然是不对的
It was definitely unhealthy,
但另一方面  我认为
but on the same token, you know, I didn't think
我本身并不坏
I was a bad person to begin with.
所以  我是说  你还想知道什么
So, you know, I mean, what, you want to know
我是否会点燃其他祖父母的房子吗
if I'm gonna light any more grandparents on fire?
-你会吗  -不会
- Are you? - No.
你还有祖父祖母在世吗
You got any more?
还有一个
Yeah, I got one.
那你应该对那位老人好些
Yeah well, try to make a better effort with that one.
我并不是专门来找你麻烦的
I'm not trying to be flip.
我觉得我应该获得自由
I think I deserve to be free, I do.
为什么  就因为你服满刑期了吗
Why, because you did the time?
就这样  你准备好了吗
That's it, you're ready?
你现在清白了吗
Now you're a clean slate?
我跟所有人一样清白  哥们
I'm clean as anybody, man.
我跟你一样清白
I'm clean as you.
也许是  也许不是
Well, maybe, maybe not.
真的  我想问问你
Seriously, let me ask you something, you know.
为什么你就能坐在那儿
Why are you- why are you- why are you gonna sit there,
问我这些问题  好像你从来没犯过错
like, asking me these questions like you never done nothin'?
为什么你能自由地进来出去而我就不能
I mean, you know, why do you get to walk around free and I don't?
我从没有犯过罪
I wasn't convicted of a crime.
得了吧  你就没做过坏事
Oh, come on, you never did anything bad?
没有对任何人做过错事
Never did anybody no wrong,
从不需要得到宽恕
had to be forgiven for nothin'?
没有  我从没有违法
No, never broke the law.
你就从没有接到超速罚单
What, you never got a speeding ticket?
没有跟别人在酒吧里打过架
You never backed somebody up in a bar fight or something?
在越南  你没有杀害过小孩
Shit, Vietnam you never killed some kid- you carry that with you?
对你太太不忠
You step out on your wife,
或者猥亵一个侧目看你的15岁小孩
you fuck that little 15-year-old who looked at you sideways?
好了  好了
Okay okay.
不  得了吧  伙计  得了吧
No, come on, man! Come on!
你还要这样判定别人多久
How long you get to keep
就因为一个人做了一件坏事
judgin' a person for
你就判定他是个坏人
one had thing they done?
无论我付出多大代价
No matter how much I paid,
都得在这儿和你废话
I gotta keep eatin' shit with you?
你还要这样多久
For how long?
不应该这样  不应该
That ain't right. It ain't.
我求你了  求你了
I mean, I'm beggin' you, man. I'm beggin' you.
我是一个人  一个人  看看我的记录
I'm a person. I'm a person. Look at my record, you know.
看看我在这儿都干了什么
Look at- look at what I've done in here.
我跟刚来的时候不一样了
I mean, I'm different than when I come in here, man.
我长大了  我他妈重获新生了
I've grown a lot. I'm like fuckin' reborn, man.
这对你的意义是什么  重获新生
What does that mean to you, being reborn?
什么
What?
重获新生对你来说是什么意思
What does that mean to you?
嗨  我又来了
Hi. Yeah, I'm back.
科里森太太
Hey, Mrs. Creeson.
你好  吉可
Hey, Jake.
谢谢  拜拜
Thanks. Bye, guys.
科里森
Creeson!
这些小辫很漂亮
Oh, the rows look so nice.
我喜欢他们的厚度  亲爱的
I like 'em thick, baby.
-是吗  -它看起来真棒
- Yeah? - It looks really good.
-我用了你送我的摩丝  -是吗
- I've been using that mousse you sent. - Yeah?
因为克里斯托告诉我睡前弄好
'Cause Crystal said you put the rag on before you go to sleep,
醒来后他们还是
and when you wake up they're
漂亮有型  他们看起来太棒了
still all clean and nice- they look really good.
他们很紧  你看起来真他妈不错
They look tight. You look so fucking good.
我好想你
I miss you so much.
你有什么新消息吗
What have you got to tell me? I mean...
我给他打过电话
Well, I called him
但是他没有回我  我又留了言
and he didn't call me back, so I left another message.
好的  很好  但是你...
Okay, that's good, but you
你得单独跟他会面
know you got to get with him person to person.
我正在努力  亲爱的  我正努力
I'm on it. Baby, I'm on it.
一对一  你知道我的意思
One on one, you know what I'm saying?
我只能让你帮我了  我一个人不行
I gotta have you with me on it. I can't do this by myself.
任何事情
Anything.
我会为你做任何事情  你知道的  对吧
I would do anything for you, you know that, right?
是的
Yeah.
好了  好了
Okay okay.
亲爱的  我今天为你穿了特别的
Baby, I wore something special for you.
是吗  你穿了什么
Did you? What did you wear?
-什么都没穿  -哦  天啊
- Nothing. - Oh God.
我服了你
You're killin' me.
不行  好了  好了
Oh no. Okay okay okay.
-什么  -过分了  不行
- What? - This is too much. No no.
不行  不  对不起  别这样  来这边
Come on. No no, I'm sorry. Just come on. Come here, come here.
亲爱的
Honey?
我没有拿到假释
I can't get no ticket.
我拿不到  你明白吗
I can't get a ticket, you understand, right?
我已经很接近了
I'm too close.
-宝贝  宝贝  -是的  是的
- Baby. Baby. - Yeah. Yeah.
我已经很接近了
Okay, I'm so close.
-我该怎么办  -会好的
- What am I gonna do? - It's gonna happen.
-我不能再这样了  -别担心
- I can't do much more of this. - Don't worry.
不行  我搞不定了
I can't. I ain't gonna make it.
我是认真的  露西塔
I'm serious, Lucetta.
我觉得  我觉得  我都想自杀了
I just think I want- like I want to kill myself.
别这样开玩笑  行吗
You don't even joke like that, okay?
别开玩笑
Don't joke.
我爱你
I love you.
你想吃点什么吗  我拿了些奶油松饼
You want something to eat? I got some cream puffs
还有些动物饼干  还有牛奶
and some animal crackers and some milk and stuff.
"让主因我而荣耀..." [约翰福音 14：13]
"That the Father may be glorified... "
基督
音禅的力量
"宽恕罪恶  那么那人
"... the embrace of sin, the individual
就能聆听到上帝的声音
achieves perfect metaphysical pitch
然后将自己
and transforms himself
变成上帝的调音叉"
into a tuning fork of God. "
我正在自我进化  你们这些狗娘养的
I'm trying improve myself here, you motherfuckers!
这是杰克和马蒂林・玛布里的家
This is Jack and Madylyn Mabry.
请留言
Please leave a message.
你好  我是露西塔・科里森
Hi. Hey, this is Lucetta Creeson.
我之前打过电话
Um, I called before.
我是杰拉德・科里森的妻子
I'm Stoney Creeson's wife.
我跟玛布里太太通过话
I spoke to Mrs. Mabry,
但是玛布里先生  我找的是你
but Mr. Mabry, this is for you.
我想跟你谈谈我丈夫的事情
I would like to talk to you about my husband.
这对我们很重要
Um, it's kind of important to us.
我一般早上工作
And I work most mornings, but-
但是  不  我可以重新安排
well, no, look, I could rearrange things,
所以  任何时间如果你方便都行
so whenever's good for you is fine with me.
见鬼
Shit.
我还没说完
I wasn't done.
谁会九点睡觉
Who goes to sleep at 9:00?
玛布里先生
Mr. Mabry?
-玛布里警官  -对不起
- Officer Mabry? - Sorry?
我是科里森太太
Mrs. Creeson...
我是石头的妻子
I'm Stoney's wife.
科里森夫人
Oh oh, Mrs. Creeson.
叫我露西塔吧  拜托
Look, call me Lucetta though, please.
你来看你的丈夫
You're here to see your husband?
不  别傻了  我来这找你
No, silly, I'm here to see you.
等等  对不起  你没有听我的留言吗
Wait, I'm sorry, didn't you get my message?
是的  好吧
Oh yeah, okay. Well,
科里森太太  我们只能
there's a way to meet with family, Mrs. Creeson.
在办公室里接见犯人亲属
You have to go through the office for me to see you.
-好吧  -案件警官接见
- Oh right. - The case officer to...
和评估家庭状况
meet and assess the home situation.
-这是我们的规定  -是这样  警官
- That's-that's how we. - See, that's the thing though, sir,
因为  我就是那个"家庭状况"
because, I mean, I am the home situation.
科里森太太
Mrs. Creeson,
-请给我办公室打电话  - 露西塔
- just call the office... - Lucetta.
露西塔  请给我办公室打电话
Lucetta. Just call the office
然后约个时间
and make an appointment.
您必须这样做
That's the way you have to do it.
我不能跟您说几句话吗
Can't I just talk to you for a while?
我是说  我们不能
I mean, can't we just,
就你我  然后约个时间吗
sort of just you and me make a date or something?
-不  不行  -求你了  求你了
- No, we can't. - Please, please.
你知道这对我们意义重大
You know how much this means to us.
如果你来看你的丈夫
If you're coming to see your husband,
没问题  但是其他任何事情不可以
fine, but we can't do it any other way.
而且我要晚了  真的
And I'm late, really.
好吧  玛布里先生
Well, Mr. Mabry,
玛布里先生  我想给你一个小礼物
Mr. Mabry, I wanted to give you a little something
这是我班上的孩子做的
my kids made in class.
不  我不能接受礼物
Yeah, I can't accept that.
这不合适  谢谢
It's inappropriate. Thank you anyway.
但这是给小鸟做的  看
But it's for the birds, see?
这是个鸟巢  它们飞来飞去编制的窝
And they- it's a nest and they come and they take their twine
它们衔来的树枝做成的小家
and their twigs and stuff and they make their little home.
谢谢
Thank you.
好的
Okay.
-很高兴见到你  -谢谢
- Nice to meet you. - Thank you.
好了
Okay.
这到底是什么
What the hell is this?
-什么东西  -这个  你妻子给的
- What's that? - This...your wife.
什么  她寄给你的吗
What, she sent it to you?
她刚才在停车场给我的
She gave it to me in the parking lot just now.
等等  什么  露西塔来找你了吗
Wait, what, Lucetta come and find you?
她刚刚在停车场给我的  别想捣乱
She gave that to me in the parking lot. Don't mess with me.
我不想给你带来任何麻烦
I ain't lookin' for any kind of trouble with you, you know.
我希望你没有把她牵扯进来
I hope you didn't put her up to it.
到时候假释小组直接给你寄驳回书
The parole board's gonna send you a flop in the mail
你连申辩的机会都不会有
and you won't even see them.
露西塔想干什么是她的事
Lucetta does whatever the fuck she wants.
我跟你说
I told you, man.
她就是喜欢这些小孩子的玩意儿
She's just boisterous.
上帝啊  真是倒霉的一周
Jesus, what a week.
我想知道你对这个怎么看
Hey hey, I want to see what you think about something.
你看过这个吗
You ever- you seen this?
我在图书馆找到的
I found it in the library.
《音禅  上帝的声音和生命》
"Zukangor, The Sound and Life God."
是的  你知道它吗
Yeah, you know it?
不
No.
书里说  声音是一切的开始
They say the sound part come first.
他说  如果你感受到了
They say the- when you experience
心灵世界的真理
a spiritual truth
它会通过声音来到你身边
that it comes to you as a sound,
穿透你的身体
that it goes through you,
改变你的震频  让你回归和谐
changes your vibration, gets you back into harmony.
就像上帝的调音叉
Like God's tuning fork or something.
如果你身体上发生这些变化
And then if you let that happen to you,
你就会得到光明
then- then you get the light,
得到启示什么的
or you get illumination or something.
我没听过这些  我是主教派的
I wouldn't know about that. I'm an Episcopalian.
他们说  要从小事开始
They say it starts with small things,
比如一些小声音  小震动
like little sounds, little vibrations,
比如电灯的嗡嗡声
like a-just like a buzzing electric light
水流声  或者蜜蜂的声音
or rushing water or the sound of a bee or...
-是吗  -是的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
然后就会发展
And then it grows.
但是这不用教父什么的  它不像宗教
But there's no priest or nothing. It's not like a religion.
就是一个叫阿诺德的人
There's just this one dude named Arnold
他是创始人
who's the Zukmaster.
书上说  你可以自己练习
They say you do this practice all by yourself.
你可以听得更好
You can- you can hear better.
你可以通过声音听到上帝对你说话
You can hear God speaking to you through sounds.
什么练习
What's the practice?
-他们吟唱"Hue"  -Hue
- They chant "Hue. " - Hue?
-然后他们聆听  -听什么  蜜蜂吗
- And then they listen. - For what, a bee?
可能吧  我不知道
Maybe, I don't know.
但是  关键是
But you know, the thing is
他们说你会不断轮回
they say you got to keep coming back
直到你偿还所有的罪孽
until you pay for all your shit.
你会用几辈子的时间来偿还
That you've got to fix it
直到所有罪孽都清算干净
over a lot of lives, you know, until you work it all out.
好吧  那这辈子呢
Well, what about this life?
你这辈子做的事情呢
What about answering for
你该如何偿还
the things that you've done in this life?
见鬼  我知道我已经偿还了
Shit, I know I have.
是吗
Have you?
是的  你呢
Yeah. Have you?
这是耶稣的身体  赐予你
This is the body of Christ, given for you.
耶稣的身体  赐予你
The body of Christ, given for you.
-我一会儿回来  -好的
- I'll be right back. - Sure.
给你  你开车回家
Here, you drive home.
我去跟牧师聊一会儿  然后自己走回去
I'm going to talk to the pastor a minute and then I'll walk.
好的
Okay.
嘿  傻子 婊子
Hey yo, foul, bitch!
可恶  你这个傻子
Damn, that's a hard foul!
这个蠢驴
Yo, that's a foul!
Hue
Hue...
伙计  你应该扣下去的
Man, you should've dunked it!
好的  我以前从没这样做过
Okay, I've never done this before, so-
我是说  我每周
well, I mean, I come to the...
都来教堂  我努力尝试
Church every week and I really try.
但是我不知道  我本来希望
And I don't know, I mean, I guess I had hoped with time
随着时间会越来越容易
it would be easier and easier and...
而且
And I'd be...
我的家人  身边的人
My family, people close to me,
对于他们似乎都很容易  但是对我
it seems to come to them easily, but for me it's...
我是说
I mean I've...
我不知道
I don't know.
我是说
I mean I've...
有时我的想法
Sometimes the thoughts that I have,
我的感觉...
feelings...
但是  有时
But, uh, sometimes
我只觉得你应该枪毙了我或怎样
I just think maybe you should shoot me or something.
我认为这不是上帝的旨意
Well, I don't believe that that's what God wants for you.
好吧  那他要怎么样
Well, what does he want?
我希望我能有个简单的答案
I wish I had a simple answer for you.
我不确定上帝想让你干什么
I'm not sure what God wants for you.
是否有...
Is there anything...
圣经有篇古老的短文说
There's an old Biblical passage that says...
"静心  吾乃上帝"
"Be still and know that I am God. "
也就是说
Which is a way of saying
有时上帝确实
sometimes God does, um,
会以神秘的方式向我们说话
speak to us in mysterious ways.
离开护栏
Off the rail!
我说  离开护栏
I said off the rail!
你好
Hello?
嗨  我是露西塔・科里森  我们上星期谈过
Hi, this is Lucetta Creeson. We talked last week.
抱歉  再说下你名字?
I'm sorry, what is your name again?
露西塔・科里森
Lucetta Creeson.
我只想问下杰克在不在家
I was just wondering if Jack was home.
恐怕他还在  等等  别挂
I'm afraid he's still- oh no, wait, hold on.
-杰克  电话  -是谁
- Jack, telephone.  - Who is it? Who? Who is it?
你的一个朋友?
A friend of yours?
-你好  -嘿
- Hello.  - Hey.
我是露西塔・科里森
It's Lucetta Creeson.
我只想问
Listen, I was just wondering, um,
我们什么时候可以见个面
when we could meet, when we could get together.
科里森夫人  我不知你怎么弄到我家电话的
Uh, Mrs. Creeson, I don't know how you're calling my house,
但我告诉过你打给办公室
but I told you to call the office.
我只是
Well, look, I'm just,
不擅长办公  而且
I'm not that great at offices and, you know,
在办公室我说不了真心话
I just- I just can't be real, like, in an office, you know?
-科里森夫人  -露西塔
- Look, Mrs. Creeson  - Lucetta.
科里森夫人  我在审核你丈夫的档案
Mrs. Creeson, I have business with your husband.
正因为这样我才打电话
Well, that's why I'm calling.
你觉得还有其他原因吗
I mean, what, did you think I had another reason?
没有  我没那样想
Well, no, I didn't.
或许我们可以一起午餐
Maybe we could go to lunch,
你可以带上玛布里夫人
you could bring Mrs. Mabry too.
她声音很甜  她的名是什么来着
You know, she's got a sweet voice. What's her first name?
听着  我很欣赏你如此爱你丈夫
Look, I admire that you love your husband
想给他帮忙
and you want to do what's right for him,
但我现在告诉你  你这是在帮倒忙
but you're not helping him. I'm telling you that right now.
听我说  杰克
Listen to me, Jack.
我的确爱我丈夫
I do love my husband.
我如此
I love my husband
爱我丈夫
so much.
我所要求的只是一个
And all I'm asking you is for a chance
帮助你从不同角度认识他的机会
to help you see him in a different light.
我是说  你工作那地方有多少人
I mean, how many men at that place you work at
会有这样爱他们的女人
have somebody loving them like that, huh?
难道这都不能让你动下恻隐之心吗
Doesn't that mean something to you,
你手中控制的可是他人的命运啊
a man in a position like yours?
这  确实  别误会我
It-it- no, it-it does, it does. Don't misunderstand me.
我只想要他回家
I just want him home.
我如此  需要他
I want... I want him so bad.
我要他拥抱我
I want his arms around me.
我要他在我床上
I want him in my bed.
我想念他
I miss him.
我不能说服你么
Can't I persuade you?
受伤的会是谁
Who's it gonna hurt, hmm?
就让我来见你吧  拜托
Just let me come see you, please.
让我来见你  杰克
Let me come see you, Jack.
我吊上他了
I got him.
会搞定的  宝贝
It's gonna happen, baby.
甜心  你没事吧
Huh. Honey, you okay?
我太他妈累了
I'm so fuckin' tired.
睡不着吗
Can't you sleep?
这里一直吵个不停
No, it's too loud all the time.
吵得我无法
So noisy I can't...
我无法静下心来
I can't get out of my head.
什么都听不到
I can't hear nothin'. I can't listen.
这地方开始让我头脑混乱了
This place is startin' to mess with my head.
跟你说  我最近在做很奇怪的梦
I'm tellin' you, I'm having these weird~ass dreams.
可怜
Poor honey.
我想自杀
I thought I wanted to kill myself, right?
想找个偏僻的地方把自己吊死
Thought I wanted to hang myself in the solitary.
我不明白  你做那种梦?
I don't get it. You dreamed that?
但接着我又非常害怕死掉
But then I got too scared to die
于是就迷茫  永无止境地待在那儿
and I just hung there for all of eternity.
我他妈不想待在这儿
I don't want to fuckin' be here.
甜心
Honey.
你那晚吃了什么
Honey, what'd you have to eat that night?
肯定是吃了什么东西  太辣了?
It must've been something. Was it spicy?
-投篮  -好  走吧
- Shoot it!  - All right, let's go.
那就是我一直和你说的我孙子
That's the grandson I've been tellin' you about right there.
-真可爱  -他眼睛这么
- How cute.  - His eyes are so...
我有个孙女
I got a grandchild.
你真有?
Do you really?
嗯  她名叫凯蒂  3岁大
Yeah. Her name's Katie, three years old.
-真可爱  -嗯  非常可爱
- Cute.  - Oh, yeah. Yeah, very cute.
她像你吗
Does she look like you?
好在不像我
Hell no. No no no.
但我想她一定爱你
I bet she loves you though.
-其实  -你经常见她吗
- Yeah well...  - You see her much?
他们住在州北部  所以不常见
They live upstate, so we don't see her that much.
那太糟糕了
Aw, that's too bad.
她正在办离婚  我女儿
She's getting a divorce, my daughter.
-抱歉  -你能怎样呢
- I'm sorry.  - What are you gonna do?
注定要发生的事情总会发生
People are gonna do what they're gonna do.
你疼痛?
Are you in pain?
嗯  是我的背
Yeah, it's just my back.
你怎么得的
Oh. What'd you get that,
打球还是打仗得的?
playing ball or like from some war?
没有  只是老年病
No no, it's just life.
我不知我是否能...
So I don't know if I can-
我不想让你空欢喜
I don't want you to get your hopes up.
欢喜什么
About what?
我对你丈夫所能做的帮助
What I can do for you, for your husband.
-这是一整个系统  -你试过磁疗吗
- There's a whole system  - Have you tried magnet therapy?
治你的背  我是说
For your back, I mean.
就是让你穿戴磁铁之类的东西
It's like these magnets that you wear and stuff.
-磁铁吗  -对  非常好的
- Magnets?  - Yeah, it's really good.
实际上  有空你应该过来坐坐
Actually, you should come over sometime,
有个家伙卖给我这些鞋垫
because I got these insoles this guy sold me
我把它们穿在鞋里后
and I wear 'em in my shoes
我在学校都不会觉得累
and I don't get tired in school or anything.
有时
And- yeah, and sometimes
我睡前还把它们放在枕头下
I even put 'em under my pillow before I go to sleep.
那样有什么用
And what does that do?
是这样
Well, okay,
你知道  我们生活的世界
you know how we're all toxic and stuff, right,
空中充满微波  手机辐射
with like all the microwaves and cell phones
和其他奇怪漂浮物  我们都中了毒
and all that weird stuff flying through the air.
在你的体内慢慢聚集
So it all builds up inside of you, right,
让你疼痛或心烦意乱
and it makes you all achy and upset-
还会让你得脑瘤  真的
and it can give you brain tumors, really-
我是说  这能让人丧命
I mean, it kills people.
而这些磁铁  可以帮你解毒
So these magnets, they detox you.
-哇  这真是  -嗯  是真的  我相信
- Wow, that's...  - Yeah, it's real. I believe it.
你不信吗
You don't believe it?
我不知道
I don't know, I guess.
是真的
No, it's real.
我很爱护身体
I mean, look, I'm all into the body, you know,
对我来说  身体感觉好了
and for me if the body's feeling good,
头脑也会清醒爽朗不少
the mind just follows, you know?
绝对是这样
Absolutely.
鸡蛋?
Egg?
我的孩子们做的
My kids made 'em.
现在都到我这了  我得全吃掉
Now I got 'em all and I have to eat 'em.
真不错  很漂亮
They're nice. They're pretty.
吃了我吧  拜托
Eat me please.
为何不呢
Why not?
我只吃有益健康的部分
I'm just eating the healthy part.
继续  全吃了
Go on, just eat the whole thing.
科里森  怎么了
Creeson, what's up?
你两天没吃东西了
You haven't been to chow in two days.
你得去医务室检查检查  把衣服穿上
You got a call out to go to Medical. Get dressed.
在那儿等等
Hold up there.
感觉到什么没
You feel anything?
没
No.
有点像刺痛的感觉
Like a tingling?
没  没什么感觉
No, I don't. I don't think I...
像有种拉力
Like a pull?
不会那么明显
It's not dramatic, you know.
只是某种感觉
It's just- it's kind of a sense.
或许有点什么吧
Yeah well, you know, maybe a little something.
嗯
Yeah.
"我遵从上帝的承诺
"To what extent is my commitment to obey God
有多少是基于信条与戒律
based on dos and don'ts
又有多少是出于对他的真爱呢"
or on a true love for Him?"
"在近期哪些时候我感到了上帝的指引"
"In what recent circumstance was I aware of God's leading?"
你来说感恩祷告吧
Why don't you say the blessing?
嗯
Yeah.
感谢主
Blessed O Lord...
blessed O Lord,
赐予食物与您的仁爱
this food to our use, and us to Thy loving service,
让我们能够留意到他人的需求
and... make us mindful of the needs of others...
-以基督之名  阿门  - 阿门
- In Christ's name, Amen.  - Amen.
你失神了吗
You lose your place?
要鸡蛋吗
You want an egg?
罪恶从出生时就跟随着我们
Sin comes naturally to us from our birth.
它是自生而得的
We-we- it's inbred in us.
做了罪恶之事并不表示我们就是罪人
We are not sinners because we sin;
做恶事是因为我们本身就是罪人
we sin because we are sinners.
即使你过了完全公正的一生
Even if you lived a life of perfect righteousness,
你也值得入地狱  知道为什么吗
you deserve hell. You know why?
因为艾赛亚说  "我们所有的公正
Because "All of our righteousnesses," Isaiah says,
也正如肮脏的邪恶"
"Are as filthy rags. "
你真的很棒  杰克
You're real sweet, Jack.
你真的很棒很棒
You're real sweet.
再猛点
Fuck me harder.
你很棒  杰克
You're good, Jack.
你是个大好人  帮助我们
You're a good man for helping us,
我很感激
I appreciate it.
你要明白不能有人知道这事
You know that nobody can know about this.
你懂的  对吧
You know that, right?
任何人都不能知道
I mean nobody.
这非常重要
That's very important.
不管你要什么  如果有人知道就完蛋了
Whatever you want, it'll all go bad if anybody knows.
大家都完蛋  你明白吗
Bad for everybody, you understand that?
当然  傻瓜
Of course, silly.
怎么了  你不吃吗
What's wrong? You're not eating?
你是否曾想过他们所说的那些永恒的东西
You ever think about things they say go on forever?
什么
What?
他们所说的永恒的东西
Things they say go on forever- like...
你知道那到底是什么意思吗
What's that mean, you know?
比如说天空  他们说天空是永恒的
The sky, like, they say the sky goes on forever.
但它究竟是什么  它是
But what is that really? That's-
我意思是  你不会了解你看不到的东西
I mean, you can't see nothing you can't see, so...
天空就像在你头顶的巨大的蓝色大碗
It's like a big bowl of blue above you.
白天你能看到云朵
You can see clouds during the day
晚上或许你能看到星星
or you can see stars at night maybe,
但就算用望远镜  你也看不到无穷
but even with a telescope you can't see forever.
所以他们怎么能知道
So how do they know?
知道什么
Know what?
知道天空到底是什么
What it is.
永恒  他们又是怎么知道的
Eternity- how do they know?
那么  杰克
So- so, Jack,
他说委员会会复查整件事
he said the board's gonna review the whole thing, okay?
他们会考虑
And they're going to take into consideration
你的年龄和
your age and, you know,
你妈  所有的因素
your mom and all that,
还有那时你曾是瘾君子的事实
and the fact that you were an addict back then, um...
-石头宝贝  -嗯?
- Hey, Stoney baby?  - Hmm?
看着我
Look at me.
我在告诉你假释的事
Well, I was trying to tell you about your parole.
嗯
Yeah?
你没有在听
Well, you weren't listening.
我在听着的
Oh yeah, I'm listening.
我有在听
I am.
好  杰克说
Okay, so Jack said, um-
你叫他杰克?
You call him Jack?
当然
Sure.
很好  他说了什么
That's good. What's he say?
他会和你谈
Okay, so, um, he's gonna talk to you
他会重新审核你的档案
and he's going over the whole thing
几天之内他就会总结
and he's gonna decide in a
对你这案件的意见
few days to write up his notes in your case file
然后递交给假释委员会
to submit it to the parole
他们下星期重审的时候
commission so when they go over it next week
就可以看到他的总结
they're gonna see it.
这难道不棒吗  宝贝
Isn't that great, baby?
甜心  就要成功了  这难道不棒吗
Honey, this could be it. Isn't that great?
嗯
Yeah.
我做得还不够好吗
Didn't-didn't-didn't I do good?
看着我
Well, look at me.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
有时我觉得  最好的事
Sometimes I think the best thing is...
就是聆听
Is just-just listen.
别装了行吗
Would you stop playin'?
你认为天国是个安宁的国度吗
Is the kingdom of heaven you think it should be a peaceful kingdom
我们会和谐相处吗
And we should all get along?
如果是那样最好  但这也可能是为了把
That's great, but is it just going
天国搬到地球这个同样是主创造的世界
to be a constant struggle...
而做的无休无止的斗争
...to have the kingdom of heaven here on earth, one of his creation?
的确是个难以定夺
That's a tough one.
打开53
Crack 53!
只要告诉我是30还是31号就行
Just tell me, is it the 30th or the 31st?
我受够你了
I've had about enough lip from you!
妈的  告诉我是哪天就好
God damn it, just tell me, which one is it?
把你姿态收起来  客气点  我说真的
You can button that up right now and be nice. And I mean it.
科里森到了
Creeson's here.
如何叫一个人
How do ask a person to...
把他自身经历过的东西
To explain something that-
解释给另一个
that they experienced
无法体验到
to where another person's got no way
这种不定性经历的人
to relate to the whole indefiniteness of it, you know?
你已经不信我了  是吗
You don't believe me already, do you?
我不是不信你  我只是
I'm not saying I don't believe you. I just, you know, I-
我看过带子  确实很让人吃惊
look, I've seen the tape, it's quite a thing.
但你并没有怎么样
But nothing happened to you.
我是说  你并未身在其中
I mean, you weren't involved in any way.
没错  我不知道如何去...
Yeah, look, I don't know how to even-
我不是...
I'm not-
我不知道  我...
I don't know. I-
你经历了  一个深奥的
You had, what, a profound
精神圣灵体验
spiritual epiphany.
妈的  我以前甚至从未听过那词
Shit, man, I ain't never even heard that word before.
我们不必非要谈这个
Look, we don't have to talk about it.
真的无关紧要
You know, it really don't matter.
那么...
Well...
别误会我
I mean, don't get me wrong,
我想相信这类事  但...
I'd like to believe in such things, but-
例如什么  你难道相信我吗
Like what? Like me? You believe in me?
当然  我也想信你
Sure, I'd like to believe in you too.
所以我们才会坐到这  是吧
I mean that's why we're all here, right?
哇
Wow.
好  等等  好好听着
Okay, you know, wait, look,
当时那就好像
there were something like...
一瞬间
It was just a moment.
干扰  全消失了
The static, it just all went away, you know?
我真能听见
And I could really hear,
就好像我真的能清晰听见
like I could hear clear, for real.
我也不清楚  它让我从不同角度看待事物
I don't know. It just made me see everything different.
它让我以不同方式看待自己的人生
It made me look at my life in a different way.
突然间  我能看到
It was just all of a sudden I could- I could see that
我在这儿的生活并不像我之前认为的那样
my life in here isn't empty
空洞  毫无意义
and pointless like I thought it was before.
家庭和...
Family and...
-石头  别玩了  -别玩什么
- Look, Stone, just drop it. - Drop what?
我知道你想干什么  但别干了
Well, I know what you're trying to do, but don't.
别干了  那没用的  停下吧
Just-just-just don't. It's not helping. Just stop.
嘿  听着
Hey look, man,
这对我不再重要了
it don't matter to me no more.
-什么不重要了  -我不在乎
- What doesn't matter?  - I don't care about what-
你所做的或其他人想让你做的
what you're doin' or what anybody else is tryin' to make you do.
让我做吗  什么意思
Make me do? What's that?
没人想让我做什么
Nobody's trying to make me do anything.
好
Okay.
你应做你认为正确之事  好吧
You should do what you think is right, okay?
你说我怎样就怎样  就写你的真实感受
I am whatever you say I am in there, so write what you feel.
我说真的  怎么想的就怎么写
Seriously. I mean it. I mean, judge me how you think.
-好吧  -我是说  别误会我的意思
- Well... - I mean, don't get me wrong,
我是想出去
I want to be out,
但是如果我出去了还会像以前那样混日子
but I'm gonna wrestle with the same shit if I'm out.
反而我要是不出去就能保持这样的感觉
And I'm gonna keep this feeling if I'm in.
那你现在改过自新了吗
So you're all good now?
不是  我不是说我突然一下高兴了
No, no, no. Look, I ain't sayin' I'm all happy all of a sudden.
你知道  一直以来我都很嚣张
You know, my middle finger's been up a long time, man.
我不会突然之间跟人招手微笑
I'm not just gonna start wavin' and smilin' at people.
我还是会发火  我还是会发脾气
I'm gonna pop off. I'm gonna lose my temper, and-
而且会说一些做一些让我后悔的事
and say shit and do shit that I'm gonna regret, whatever.
我只是  我就是我  你明白吗
I just- I just- I am who I am, you know?
那些都没什么  你明白我的意思吗
And that's okay. You know what I'm sayin'?
不  我想我不明白
No. No, I'm afraid I don't.
好吧  我说过我解释不清楚的
Well, I told you I couldn't explain it really.
-你没事吧  -后背不太舒服
- Are you okay? - Yeah. My back.
我去别的房间睡
I'm gonna go sleep in the other room.
你能在那里找到慰藉
You can take great comfort in that,
但那种慰藉并不是真的
but that can be a false comfort.
有时候在文明的曙光中
Sometimes in the twilight of a civilization,
伟大的文化会繁荣昌盛起来
there can be a great cultural flowering,
但事实上  那样的社会根基里存在着裂缝
but in reality, there are cracks in the foundation of that society
所以那样的社会注定在劫难逃
and that society is doomed.
如果你真的想知道...
If you really want to know,
我觉得那只是演戏什么的
I think it's some kind of play-acting or something.
那都是胡扯
It's all bullshit?
不  不  石头只是
No. No. Look, Stoney's just...
你知道的  他脑子有点混乱
You know. I mean, he's screwed up.
他对事物的看法很怪异
He's got weird ideas about things.
有时候真的很怪异
Sometimes really weird.
但是  他一直就那样
But, I mean, he's always been that way.
跟他谈话后
Talkin' to him,
我觉得他...
he almost seemed like...
他怎么了
Like what?
有点  我也说不清  不一样了
Something- really, I don't know. Different.
不会吧
No.
他只是想给你留下个好印象
Look, he-'s just trying to impress you, you know,
为了出来他什么都肯做
trying to do whatever it takes to get out.
你能因为这个责怪他吗
Can you blame him?
-不  别了  -怎么了
- No, it's okay. - What?
坐下来吧
Hey, sit down.
过来  过来坐下
Come on. Come on, sit down.
坐下
Sit down.
他很敬仰你
Look, he admires you a lot, you know.
他跟我说和你谈话学到了很多东西
He told me he learned a lot talking to you.
你能跟说实话吗
Can you be straight?
一直都在说实话呢
Straight as you.
所有这一切都只是...
Is this all just a- I mean,
告诉我到底怎么回事
just-just-just tell me what's going on.
我不会去做任何我不想做的事
I don't do anything I don't want to do.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我喜欢你  杰克
I like you, Jack.
如果我不愿意我是不